<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0">
   <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
         <titleStmt>
            <title>Articles exhibited in Parliament, against Master Iohn Squire, viccar of Saint Leonard Shoreditch, August 7th. 1641.</title>
         </titleStmt>
         <editionStmt>
            <edition>
               <date>1641</date>
            </edition>
         </editionStmt>
         <extent>Approx. 7 KB of XML-encoded text transcribed from 5 1-bit group-IV TIFF page images.</extent>
         <publicationStmt>
            <publisher>Text Creation Partnership,</publisher>
            <pubPlace>Ann Arbor, MI ; Oxford (UK) :</pubPlace>
            <date when="2013-12">2013-12 (EEBO-TCP Phase 2).</date>
            <idno type="DLPS">A75641</idno>
            <idno type="STC">Wing A3822</idno>
            <idno type="STC">Thomason E171_15</idno>
            <idno type="STC">ESTC R2095</idno>
            <idno type="EEBO-CITATION">99868376</idno>
            <idno type="PROQUEST">99868376</idno>
            <idno type="VID">157048</idno>
            <availability>
               <p>To the extent possible under law, the Text Creation Partnership has waived all copyright and related or neighboring rights to this keyboarded and encoded edition of the work described above, according to the terms of the CC0 1.0 Public Domain Dedication (http://creativecommons.org/publicdomain/zero/1.0/). This waiver does not extend to any page images or other supplementary files associated with this work, which may be protected by copyright or other license restrictions. Please go to https://www.textcreationpartnership.org/ for more information about the project.</p>
            </availability>
         </publicationStmt>
         <seriesStmt>
            <title>Early English books online.</title>
         </seriesStmt>
         <notesStmt>
            <note>(EEBO-TCP ; phase 2, no. A75641)</note>
            <note>Transcribed from: (Early English Books Online ; image set 157048)</note>
            <note>Images scanned from microfilm: (Thomason Tracts ; 30:E171[15])</note>
         </notesStmt>
         <sourceDesc>
            <biblFull>
               <titleStmt>
                  <title>Articles exhibited in Parliament, against Master Iohn Squire, viccar of Saint Leonard Shoreditch, August 7th. 1641.</title>
                  <author>England and Wales. Parliament.</author>
               </titleStmt>
               <extent>[2], 6 p.   </extent>
               <publicationStmt>
                  <publisher>s.n.],</publisher>
                  <pubPlace>[London :</pubPlace>
                  <date>Printed in the yeare, 1641.</date>
               </publicationStmt>
               <notesStmt>
                  <note>Place of publication from Wing.</note>
                  <note>Reproduction of the original in the British Library.</note>
               </notesStmt>
            </biblFull>
         </sourceDesc>
      </fileDesc>
      <encodingDesc>
         <projectDesc>
            <p>Created by converting TCP files to TEI P5 using tcp2tei.xsl,
      TEI @ Oxford.
      </p>
         </projectDesc>
         <editorialDecl>
            <p>EEBO-TCP is a partnership between the Universities of Michigan and Oxford and the publisher ProQuest to create accurately transcribed and encoded texts based on the image sets published by ProQuest via their Early English Books Online (EEBO) database (http://eebo.chadwyck.com). The general aim of EEBO-TCP is to encode one copy (usually the first edition) of every monographic English-language title published between 1473 and 1700 available in EEBO.</p>
            <p>EEBO-TCP aimed to produce large quantities of textual data within the usual project restraints of time and funding, and therefore chose to create diplomatic transcriptions (as opposed to critical editions) with light-touch, mainly structural encoding based on the Text Encoding Initiative (http://www.tei-c.org).</p>
            <p>The EEBO-TCP project was divided into two phases. The 25,368 texts created during Phase 1 of the project (2000-2009), initially available only to institutions that contributed to their creation, were released into the public domain on 1 January 2015. The approximately 40,000 texts produced during Phase 2 (2009- ), of which 34,963 had been released as of 2020, originally similarly restricted, were similarly freed from all restrictions on 1 August 2020. As of that date anyone is free to take and use these texts for any purpose (modify them, annotate them, distribute them, etc.). But we do respectfully request that due credit and attribution be given to their original source.</p>
            <p>Users should be aware of the process of creating the TCP texts, and therefore of any assumptions that can be made about the data.</p>
            <p>Text selection was based on the New Cambridge Bibliography of English Literature (NCBEL). If an author (or for an anonymous work, the title) appears in NCBEL, then their works are eligible for inclusion. Selection was intended to range over a wide variety of subject areas, to reflect the true nature of the print record of the period. In general, first editions of a works in English were prioritized, although there are a number of works in other languages, notably Latin and Welsh, included and sometimes a second or later edition of a work was chosen if there was a compelling reason to do so.</p>
            <p>Image sets were sent to external keying companies for transcription and basic encoding. Quality assurance was then carried out by editorial teams in Oxford and Michigan. 5% (or 5 pages, whichever is the greater) of each text was proofread for accuracy and those which did not meet QA standards were returned to the keyers to be redone. After proofreading, the encoding was enhanced and/or corrected and characters marked as illegible were corrected where possible up to a limit of 100 instances per text. Any remaining illegibles were encoded as &lt;gap&gt;s. Understanding these processes should make clear that, while the overall quality of TCP data is very good, some errors will remain and some readable characters will be marked as illegible. Users should bear in mind that in all likelihood such instances will never have been looked at by a TCP editor.</p>
            <p>The texts were encoded and linked to page images in accordance with level 4 of the TEI in Libraries guidelines.</p>
            <p>Copies of the texts have been issued variously as SGML (TCP schema; ASCII text with mnemonic sdata character entities); displayable XML (TCP schema; characters represented either as UTF-8 Unicode or text strings within braces); or lossless XML (TEI P5, characters represented either as UTF-8 Unicode or TEI g elements).</p>
            <p>Keying and markup guidelines are available at the <ref target="http://www.textcreationpartnership.org/docs/.">Text Creation Partnership web site</ref>.</p>
         </editorialDecl>
         <listPrefixDef>
            <prefixDef ident="tcp"
                       matchPattern="([0-9\-]+):([0-9IVX]+)"
                       replacementPattern="http://eebo.chadwyck.com/downloadtiff?vid=$1&amp;page=$2"/>
            <prefixDef ident="char"
                       matchPattern="(.+)"
                       replacementPattern="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/textcreationpartnership/Texts/master/tcpchars.xml#$1"/>
         </listPrefixDef>
      </encodingDesc>
      <profileDesc>
         <langUsage>
            <language ident="eng">eng</language>
         </langUsage>
         <textClass>
            <keywords scheme="http://authorities.loc.gov/">
               <term>Squire, John, ca. 1588-1653 --  Early works to 1800.</term>
               <term>Religious tolerance --  England --  Early works to 1800.</term>
            </keywords>
         </textClass>
      </profileDesc>
      <revisionDesc>
         <change>
            <date>2012-05</date>
            <label>TCP</label>Assigned for keying and markup</change>
         <change>
            <date>2012-06</date>
            <label>SPi Global</label>Keyed and coded from ProQuest page images</change>
         <change>
            <date>2012-07</date>
            <label>Pip Willcox</label>Sampled and proofread</change>
         <change>
            <date>2012-07</date>
            <label>Pip Willcox</label>Text and markup reviewed and edited</change>
         <change>
            <date>2013-02</date>
            <label>pfs</label>Batch review (QC) and XML conversion</change>
      </revisionDesc>
   </teiHeader>
   <text xml:lang="eng">
      <front>
         <div type="title_page">
            <pb facs="tcp:157048:1"/>
            <pb facs="tcp:157048:1" rendition="simple:additions"/>
            <p>ARTICLES EXHIBITED IN PARLIAMENT, <hi>AGAINST</hi> Maſter IOHN SQVIRE, <hi>
                  <g ref="char:V">Ʋ</g>iccar</hi> of Saint <hi>Leonard Shoreditch,</hi> Auguſt <hi>7th.</hi> 1641.</p>
            <p>Printed in the yeare, 1641.</p>
         </div>
      </front>
      <body>
         <div type="articles">
            <pb facs="tcp:157048:2"/>
            <pb n="1" facs="tcp:157048:2"/>
            <head>ARTICLES Exhibited in PARLIAMENT againſt M<hi rend="sup">r</hi>. <hi>John Squire,</hi> Viccar of St. <hi>Leonard Shoreditch,</hi> Auguſt the 7th. 1641.</head>
            <div n="1" type="article">
               <head>1.</head>
               <p>
                  <seg rend="decorInit">T</seg>Hat this <hi>Squire</hi> did arrogantly introduce many Popiſh Cere<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>monies into their Pariſh Church, Tyrannically inſulting over the conſciences, and liberties of the Pariſhioners, Commanding them to ſub<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſcribe thereunto without any interdi<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ction.</p>
            </div>
            <div n="2" type="article">
               <head>2.</head>
               <p>That he affirmed publikely in the Pul<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>pit, that the Papiſts were the Kings beſt ſubjects in three regards.</p>
               <pb n="2" facs="tcp:157048:3"/>
               <p n="1">1. In regard of their liberality, who were alwayes eady to extend their cha<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>rity, and did preſent themſelves with their purſes in their hands alwayes before his Majeſtie.</p>
               <p n="2">2. In regard of their loyalty, who did not onely ſeeme hoſpitable in their purſes, but were alwayes in their owne perſons ready to doe his Majeſtie ſer<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>vice.</p>
               <p n="3">3. In regard of their patience: who (notwithſtanding the many affronts, and perſecutions offered them by <hi>Engliſh men</hi>) have patiently ſubmitted to their cruelty, and buried all in oblivion: wherefore upon the conſideration of theſe three re<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>gards he was confident (as hee related) that they were the Kings beſt ſubjects.</p>
            </div>
            <div n="3" type="article">
               <head>3.</head>
               <p>That he called all thoſe Schiſmatickes, Who would not bow at the name of <hi>Ie<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſus;</hi> but being afterwards privately exa<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>mined upon that point he could not law<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>fully
<pb n="3" facs="tcp:157048:3"/>call thoſe Schiſmaticks which did not, unleſſe thoſe Idolaters which did.</p>
            </div>
            <div n="4" type="article">
               <head>4.</head>
               <p>That he writes himſelfe commonly <hi>Prieſt,</hi> and approves of it to be an honourable name, and diſpiſeth the nomination of Miniſter, or Paſtor, &amp;c. although wee have had ſufficient teſtimony that this name was abrogated after <hi>Chriſts</hi> comming, and more decent names gi<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ven them in the holy Goſpell.</p>
            </div>
            <div n="5" type="article">
               <head>5.</head>
               <p>That our King was like unto the wounded man that fell among theeves (the <hi>Scots</hi> by his imaginary ſuppoſition) robbing his Majeſte of his Caſtles, Holds, and withall the hearts of his ſubjects: and that the formall Confeſſors was like unto the <hi>Levite,</hi> that paſſed by; the Proteſtant like unto the <hi>Prieſt;</hi> but the <hi>Papiſts</hi> like unto the good <hi>Samaritan,</hi> who lifted up his Majeſtie from thoſe wicked Enemies to our Nation, and by their Hoſpitable benigni<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tie were very indulgent to his <hi>Majeſtie.</hi>
               </p>
            </div>
            <div n="6" type="article">
               <head>6.</head>
               <p>That it was a ſinne of damnation for any man to heare voluntarily any other <hi>Miniſter</hi> than his owne, onely three Cauſes excepted.</p>
               <list>
                  <item>1. Either going to the Chriſtning of a chid.</item>
                  <item>2. Or to an Offering.</item>
                  <pb n="4" facs="tcp:157048:4"/>
                  <item>3. Or unleſſe invited forth to Dinner.</item>
               </list>
               <p>Although St. <hi>Chriſoſtome,</hi> St. <hi>Auguſtine</hi> St. <hi>Hierome,</hi> and all the Fathers, in next Antiquity to Apoſtolicall men, doe with one aſſent af<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>firme that the Church in the Goſpell is taken Catholickely, and is univerſall.</p>
            </div>
            <div n="7" type="article">
               <head>7.</head>
               <p>That any man, which paſſed Excommu<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>nication from the <hi>Prieſt</hi> publikely in the Church, unleſſe reconciled before his death, went directly to hell in his judgement, al<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>though we have ſufficient prohibitions in the Goſpell, that no man (much leſſe a Miniſter) ſhould judge any man before the time.</p>
            </div>
            <div n="8" type="article">
               <head>8.</head>
               <p>That it was lawfull for any man to play and take any recreation on the Sabbath Day, if ſo be it were not ſervice time.</p>
            </div>
            <div n="9" type="article">
               <head>9.</head>
               <p>That he did alter the ancient Structure of the ſaid Pariſh Church, and withall did inſolently induce many Pictures therein, againſt the will, intent, and ſubſcription of any of the people, and ſuch Images, as he pleaſed without prohibition.</p>
            </div>
            <div n="10" type="article">
               <head>10.</head>
               <p>
                  <hi>That</hi> he allowed the Pictures of the <hi>Virgin
<pb n="5" facs="tcp:157048:4"/>Mary,</hi> of <hi>Chriſt,</hi> and his 12. <hi>Apoſtles</hi> at his laſt Supper in Glaſſe: and the <hi>Pariſhioners</hi> de<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſired rather that in their ſtead a Crucifixe might be erected, but he would not conde<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſcend thereunto.</p>
               <p n="11">11. That he was perſwaded thoſe had not ſafe conſciences, who would not bow with all hu<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>mility, and great reverence to the <hi>Communion-Table,</hi> both at their entrance into the Church, and at their departure thereout.</p>
               <p n="12">12. That he would not Adminiſter the holy Sacrament to thoſe which would not come up unto the Rayles, and bow thereunto with humble adoration; whereupon moſt of the Pariſhioners for conſcience ſake have (not pre<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſuming to ſubmit to this ceremony) omitted the receiving of the ſaid Sacrament.</p>
               <p n="13">13. That he did oftentimes exaſperate, and foment ſtrife and enmity betwixt neighbour and neighbour; and thoſe who would not ſubſcribe to his Ceremoniall Innovations, hee was their perfect enemies, untill many of them have beene compelled to leave that <hi>Pariſh,</hi> to the great detriment of their trades.</p>
               <p n="14">14. That he affirmed publikely in his <hi>Pulpit,</hi> that it was a damnable ſin for any man to de<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>prave or ſpeake againſt any of thoſe <hi>Canons</hi>
                  <pb n="6" facs="tcp:157048:5"/>Which were publiſhed by ſuperior authority.</p>
               <p n="15">15. That if the King ſhould demand either the lands, houſes, poſſeſſions, and whole Eſtate, nay, the very life it ſelfe of any ſubject, without any offence by him committed, unleſſe hee did voluntarily attribute, and ſurrender it unto him, that he committed a moſt abominable ſinne of damnation.</p>
               <p n="16">16. that he have brought many of his <hi>Pa<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>riſhioners</hi> into the Court, and thereby great troubles have beene incident to many, and to ſome excommunication, onely becauſe they would not ſubſcribe to theſe Ceremonies, and withall, that he have cauſed great ſedition, and diſcord in the ſaid <hi>Pariſh.</hi>
               </p>
               <p n="17">17. That in all theſe <hi>Popiſh</hi> Obſervations, and Eccleſiaſticall Ceremonies, he have been no leſſe offenſive than <hi>Canterbury</hi> himſelf, in ſome reſpect, a man prompted for exalting that <hi>Ro<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>man</hi> Religion. And to incurre the favour of many Biſhops, he have beene extreame diligent to execute all their Canons, and Ceremonies to the full extent.</p>
               <trailer>FINIS.</trailer>
            </div>
         </div>
      </body>
   </text>
</TEI>
